WYATT PREUL

Node.js Architect at nearForm



Kansas City, MO

(573) 999-1075

wpreul@gmail.com

isgeek.com

github.com/geek

SUMMARY

I have leadership experience as well as a strong technical background, which make me an ideal candidate for a developer leadership role.

I regularly contribute to open source software, namely software in the Node.js ecosystem. I helped to create hapi and the surrounding ecosystem at my time at WalmartLabs. I am an active maintainer of Seneca, lab, and other hapi related modules. I have a passion for containers, microservices, application security, and testing.

PUBLICATIONS

2015-08 Developing a hapi Edge

Bleeding Edge Press

2008-03 Professional Community Server Themes

Wiley Publishing/Wrox Press

2007-03 Professional Community Server

Wiley Publishing/Wrox Press

WORK HISTORY

2015-09 - Architect, Engineering

present nearForm

- Lead open source initiatives, namely Seneca

- Support client work by building custom tools

- Architect node.js solutions for clients

2015-05 - Engineering Manager

2015-09 WalmartLabs

- Led team to deliver customer checkin experience

- Worked with multiple teams and business leaders to deliver Node.js

services for in-store customer experiences

2014-02 - Architect, Engineering

2015-05 WalmartLabs

- Helped drive Node. js adoption at Walmart

- Supported teams and provided guidance on using Node.js

- Supported open source initiatives, namely hapi

- Architected and helped build custom analytics solution for Walmart mobile

2012-09 - Senior Software Engineer

2014-02 WalmartLabs

- Developed hapijs platform.

- Built Node js tooling to support Node.js developers

2010-10 - Application Security Lead

2012-09 Telligent

	 Conducted security reviews of software products Facilitated 3rd party security reviews of products Led efforts to improve security posture of development teams
2006-10 - 2010-10	Senior Software Engineer Telligent
	- Built and supported many features in Telligent Enterprise, which is a .NET web application
	- Developed mobile phonegap implementation of Telligent Enterprise using backbone and zepto
	- Helped QA team by building custom wrapper for Selenium to make writing tests in .NET simpler
2005-06 - 2006-08	Programmer Level 2
	HNI Corporation
	 Helped drive adoption of .NET framework Built first eCommerce site for company to sell office furniture
EDUCATION	
2001 - 2005	B.A Computer Science, Religious Studies, Minor in Classics
	Monmouth College
	Activities and Societies: - Vice President of Student Senate
	- President Eta Sigma Phi - Head Resident of Graham Hall Dormitory
PRESEN	ITATIONS
2016-02	Developing Microservices with Node.js and Docker Container Summit - NYC
2016-01	Orchestrating Mobile APIs with Node.js
2010-01	Node Community Convention -SF
2015-11	The proof is in the pudding - seneca+hapi Nodevember - Nashville
2015-10	hapines with devices
	FullStack - London
2015-09	hapi workshop
	NodeConf EU - Ireland
2014-06	hapi are the developers
	LXJS - Portugal